<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Misaki Koonce]]></title><description><![CDATA[Web Developer in training. Originally from Tokyo and now in Seattle. I enjoy frontend software development.]]></description><link>https://misakikoonce.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:51:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Brown and Cony]]></title><description><![CDATA[This page is about Brown and Cony project.
Here is the test for iframe. Source URL is from Gatsby official tutorial.]]></description><link>https://misakikoonce.com/brown-and-cony/brown-and-cony/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://misakikoonce.com/brown-and-cony/brown-and-cony/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This page is about Brown and Cony project.
Here is the test for iframe. Source URL is from Gatsby official tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Project Miguel]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is my second pure CSS project, hedgehog Miguel. I created this project to have better understanding for animation, SVG and to test how…]]></description><link>https://misakikoonce.com/project-miguel/project-miguel/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://misakikoonce.com/project-miguel/project-miguel/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is my second pure CSS project, hedgehog Miguel. I created this project to have better understanding for animation, SVG and to test how much I can create and design with pure CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to create spines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;strong&gt;font-awesome&lt;/strong&gt; for spines. I applied two certificate icons for head and body using &lt;code&gt;&amp;#x3C;i&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to create face&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those ears, eyes and nose are empty DOM element and set the size and color in CSS. I created paired items, ears and eyes, using unordered list so that it&apos;s going to easy to style them together. &lt;/br&gt;
I used SVG to create a cute little smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to create the moving feet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those tootsies are all &lt;code&gt;&amp;#x3C;div&gt;&lt;/code&gt;s. The reason I didn&apos;t use list is that I could add different animation for each of them and I could enjoy the different moves😽
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
The original positions are set used &lt;code&gt;transform: rotate(Xdeg);&lt;/code&gt;. Then I added animation for 5000 millisecond. Within the 5 second, those little feet moves back and forth because I change the &lt;code&gt;transform: rotate(Xdeg)&lt;/code&gt; in every 20% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>